Matt: Compitum routes under hard resource limits.
Matt: It had shadow prices, but did not let them choose.
Ellie: FabricPC asked: can hidden scarcity become a routing price?
Ellie: The proposed chain ended with price choosing action.
Matt: But the final link broke.
Matt: Even exact belief failed when one local price was multiplied by a lumpy action.
Matt: The predictor was not the whole problem. The steering rule itself was wrong.
Ellie: The correction prices the whole action.
Ellie: It compares future value before spending with future value after spending.
Ellie: The discrete unit charges telescope to the same two lookups: exact charge, not a tangent.
Matt: Immediate utility minus action charge now ranks choices exactly like Bellman.
Matt: Certified choices and utility matched. Mismatches: zero.
Ellie: Belief still matters.
Ellie: At one reachable state, belief point zero five selects spend; point two zero selects opportunity.
Ellie: This proves an action change, not the threshold.
Matt: The fixed FabricPC predictor did not clear its gate.
Matt: Predictive coding tied backprop at point three one four: fifteen point four percent of the recoverable gap.
Ellie: The intervention restored exact action pricing.
Ellie: The model lost. The experiment succeeded.